Mc Auriel Gagan

Test Automation Specialist

A Software Quality Assurance with 10 years of extensive professional experience in both manual and automated testing. Passionate in learning and implementing Test Automation tools; positive attitude, flexible, adapts quickly to environments, output-oriented, self-starter and team focused.

mc.auriel.gagan@gmail.com

+639176290412

www.mcaurielgagan.com

linkedin.com/in/mc-auriel-gagan in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Test Automation Engineer

OLX Group (Naspers)

Ortigas Center, Philippines

OLX is the world's leading classifieds platform, with a presence in more than 40 countries.

- Lead and established the foundation of web base and android app automated testing using PHP, Selenium Appium, Eclipse, Java, and Athena by OLX.
- Ensuring quality of web base and android app before releasing to production by executing automated regression test for each build.
- Successfully facilitated brownbag sessions to improve team capability of writing BDD (Behaviour Driven Development) test features and scripts.
- Maintained and improved Jenkins CI/CD Tools

QA Engineer

08/2016 – Present

CHAMP Cargosystems Philippines, Inc. &

08/2014 - 08/2016 Makati City

IT company working solely in the air cargo industry, providing services for carriers and distributors

- Ensured that there is no blocker and critical defect/s that will be released. Created and executed manual test cases. Worked closely with the Scrum Teams for defect/s found during regression testing.
- Successfully implemented various automated tools to improved team efficiency like checking of ERRORS in logs, automated deployment, compilation of automated test results and develop a tool to deploy specific build for testing.

Sr. Software QA Engineer

US Auto Parts Network (Philippines) Corp. &

Mandaluyong, Philippines

U.S. Auto Parts stands as one of the most trusted internet retailers online.

- Created and executed test cases to verify and validate the business and functional requirements of a E-Commerce website.
- Worked closely with project manager, business analysts and developers in analyzing business requirements and reporting defects through automated and manual functional and regression test execution.

Software Tester

Chase Technologies Corporation

Provider of point-of-sale (POS) software, cash register software, and retail solutions.

 Successfully created and executed test cases, develops user's manuals and troubleshooting procedures. Participates in software design reviews and software walkthrough. Logged defects during the test execution phase.

Associate Software Engineer

Accenture Technology Solutions &

Mandaluvona City

A leading global professional services company providing a range of strategy, consulting, digital, technology & operations services and solutions.

 Attended classroom trainings, brownbags, and seminars about fundamentals of software testing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Rizal Technological University

06/2002 - 03/2008

SKILLS



CERTIFICATES

ISTQB - BCS Certified Tester Foundation Level

ISTQB Foundation Level software testing certification (CTFL) is a career essential for those testing software. Foundation Level provides a common testing vocabulary and testing principles that make you and your team more efficient. This is an easy first step for those testing software. (License 00309504)

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Automated Web Testing (Athena)

- Simplified version how to setup Web Base automated testing using ATHENA platform
- Project Link: https://git.io/vArAE

COURSES

AWS Technical Essentials (Classroom Course) (11/2017 - 11/2017)

Architecting on AWS (Classroom Course) (11/2017 - 11/2017)

ORGANIZATIONS

Software Testing Philippines (03/2017 - Present)

Core Group Member

LANGUAGES

Filipino

Makati City

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Basketball Mountain Biking Billiards